《太空堡垒卡拉狄加》前情回顾
NARRATOR: Previously on Battlestar Galactica.
提炼船的船长仍拒绝合作
The refinery captain is still not cooperating.
又有7艘集装箱船拒绝再补给
And now, seven other container ships are refusing to release their supplies.
去他妈的  我要派陆战队
Frak this! I'm sending in the marines.
告诉他们去那里拿回补给
TIGH: Tell them to get over there and bring back the supplies.
大家  退后  知道吗
People, step back, all right?
我们只是来拿补给品的
We're just here for the supplies. All right?
别挡道  不要有人因此受伤
Stay out of our way, and no one gets hurt.
停火  停火
Cease fire! Cease fire!
你们向他们射击就因为他们扔咖啡
You shot people for throwing coffee.
当时人群失去了控制
The crowd was out of control.
有人开了一枪  我不知道是谁
Somebody took a shot. I don't know who it was.
然后就一片混乱  那是一场意外
Then all hell broke loose. It was an accident.
你想让我怎样  西洛    她是赛昂人
What do you want from me, Helo? She's a Cylon.
我不会让你杀了她  知道吗
I'm not going to let you kill her. Okay?
她怀了我的孩子
She's carrying my child.
我真的挺好的
I'm okay, really.
恩
Yeah.
我不想让我们的孩子生在这牢房里
It's just, I don't want a baby born in a cell.
大家  退后  知道吗? 我们只是来拿补给品的
People, just step back. Stay back, all right? We just need some supplies.
挡住他们!挡住他们!
Get them back. Get them back.
停火!
Cease fire!
急救员快来!
Medic. We need a medic in here, now.
爸爸
GIRL: Dad!
我的天呀
Oh, my gods!
这是近来刚被曝光的片段
D'ANNA: This recently discovered footage
它取自众所周知的"吉迪恩惨案"
from what's become known as the Gideon Massacre
里面记录了卡拉狄加上的陆战队员
appears to show Galactica's marines firing indiscriminately
不分青红皂白地向手无寸铁的平民开枪射击
into a crowd of unarmed civilians.
4人死亡  12人受伤
Four dead, 12 wounded.
然而  时至今日  卷入此事件的…
And yet, as of today, not a single charge has been filed
陆战队员和指挥官员 仍未受到任何指控
against any of the marines involved, nor their commanding officers.
这是来自戴安娜·贝丝的报道
This is D'Anna Biers, reporting.
这将让整件事大白于天下
D'ANNA: That's gonna blow this thing wide open.
我们需要一些狂怒的陆战队员的底片材料
We need some stock footage of raging marines.
可以用来与目击证人的证词互相插播
We can intercut that with the eyewitness statements.
你们没权力就这样进来
You've no right to come in here like this.
女士  你要和我们走一趟
Ma'am, you're to come with us.
怎么  要逮捕我?
What, am I under arrest?
不  女士
No, ma'am.
如果我不答应呢?
And what if I refuse to go?
你好  贝丝女士
Hello, Miss Biers.
很高兴见到你  欢迎你来到殖民者一号
It's nice to see you. Welcome to Colonial One.
总统女士  这是我的荣幸
Madam President, it's an honor.
阿达玛指挥官
Cmdr. Adama.
录象带是哪里来的?
Where did you get the tape?
一位匿名的爱国者
From an anonymous patriot.
这算是社交活动 还是说我们又要政变了?
So, is this a social call or are we on the verge of another coup?
有意思
Funny.
只是想活跃一下气氛
Just something to break the ice.
我来这里是因为二位对我"吉迪恩惨案"的报道不满吧
I take it I'm here because you are unhappy with my story on the Gideon Massacre?
在吉迪恩上所发生的一切是一场悲剧
What happened aboard the Gideon was a tragedy.
可那并不是惨案
But it was not a massacre.
但录象带上显示的却是你的人向一群手无寸铁的平民开枪
But the tape shows your men firing into a crowd of defenseless civilians.
我的队员们讲述的却是另一回事
My marines tell a different story.
对我来说都一样
Not to me.
我已经递交了一打采访申请 可都被回绝了
I've submitted a dozen interview requests, all denied.
这事情即将有所改变
Well, that's about to change.
几个月来你一直想要制作一个卡拉狄加上船员生活的故事
You've been lobbying to do a story on the Galactica for months.
阿达玛指挥官已同意你可以无限制地访问船员和出入船上
Cmdr. Adama has agreed to give you unlimited access to his crew and his ship.
对  无限制
That's right. Unlimited access.
这么做也不会免费宣传你们
All access won't buy you a propaganda piece.
我们不想要
We don't want one.
贝丝女士  你的这盘录象带把即将平息的事情又拿了出来
Miss Biers, this tape of yours has put fuel on a fire that was about to die.
人们怒不可竭  他们不信任军队
People are angry, they are distrustful of the military.
事出有因  女士
Yeah, with good reason, ma'am.
有些时候是事出有因
In some cases, with good reason.
但我想为大家展示的是卡拉狄加上的真实生活
But I want to show the people what life aboard the Galactica is really like.
让大家见识一下每天保护我们免受赛昂人袭击的那些人
I want to put a human face on the officers and the crew
捍卫我们自由的那些人 他们生活中的一面
who protect us against Cylons and guard our freedoms every day.
你要是看到了那一面 可能就不会喜欢了
You might not like that face when you see it.
那又会怎样?
What would that be?
我们想要的
ROSLIN: All we really want
就是一个公平的故事
is a balanced story.
向我们展示一下卡拉狄加上男女们的真实的一面
Show us what the men and women of Galactica are really like.
这就行了?      这就行
That's it? That's it.
在发生内乱之前快着手去做吧
And I need you to do it now before we tear each other apart.
空军指挥官最好开始想点办法了
The CAG had better start cracking some heads.
我们的一半补给品都滞后到达
Half our supply runs are behind schedule.
作战信息中心  我是杜亚拉
Combat, Dualla.
上校  是你的太太 事情有些不对劲
Colonel, it's your wife. Something's wrong.
上校
Colonel.
艾伦  你没事吧?
Ellen, are you okay?
索尔  老天
Oh, Saul, gods.
我好害怕
Oh, I'm so scared.
"你必将落入黑暗之中"
TIGH: "From the darkness, you must fall. "
那是什么意思?
What does it mean?
雷丝克 这是哪来的?
Racetrack, where did you get these?
抱歉  长官  有次运送平民的时候留下的
Sorry, sir, they were left over from a civilian run.
我一直想丢掉的
I've been meaning to throw them out.
不
No.
放个安全的地方  保管好
ADAMA: Put them in a safe place. Hold on to them.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
你在拍吗?
You filming this?
我们从殖民者一号开始就在拍了
D'ANNA: We've been rolling since Colonial One.
总统说过没有限制的
The President did say, "Total access. "
是的
You'll have that.
可一旦拍摄到任何会危及战舰安全的东西
But you start shooting anything that compromises the safety of the ship,
就会被剪掉
and it will be cut.
你所听到的嘶嘶声是氧气再循环装置
DUALLA: That hiss you hear is an oxygen recirc unit.
卡拉狄加上有12个二氧化碳涤气器
We have about a dozen CO2 scrubbers aboard Galactica.
全天24小时运转
They all work 24 hours a day.
拍个特效镜头好吗  贝尔?
Get a close-up of that, would you, Bill?
恩  好的
Yeah, sure.
我们刚完成15小时的轮流值班
We just finished a 15-hour rotation.
恩  你最好赶快适应吧
Yeah, well, you better get used to it.
我们在舰队里没找到傻蛋之前
We may be short on pilots till the rest of the fleet pulls the stick
驾驶员一直短缺
out of its collective fat ass.
泰的"光辉时刻"又泄露了出来？
More fall-out from Tigh's moment of glory?
你听说他受死亡威胁了?
You heard about his death threat?
好人不会遇到这事
Couldn't have happened to a nicer guy.
我只是不敢相信自己还没被找去接受审问
I just can't believe that I haven't been called in for questioning yet.
你是主要对象
Oh, you were top of the list.
但别担心  我会告诉泰除非太阳打西边出来
But don't worry. I told Tigh that you wouldn't know Caprican poetry
不然你可不懂卡布里卡的诗歌
if it was hot-soldered across your helmet.
"你必将落入黑暗之中
"From the darkness, you must fall,
失败  软弱之人  都将陷入黑暗"
"failed and weak, to darkness all. "
柯泰洛斯写的 并不是他最好的作品
Kataris. Not one of his best.
我还可以当嫌犯吗?    求你了
Can I be a suspect again? Please.
下一个地方就是厨房了
DUALLA: Ship's galley is next on the itinerary.
为保持新鲜  我们的蔬菜及罐头食品
Our vegetable stores and canned goods are kept in titanium lockers
都放在钛制的储藏库里
to ensure maximum freshness.
走了这么远可不是为了喝口汤的
I didn't come all this way to interview the soup of the day.
女士
DUALLA: Ma'am?
小天天和小甜甜来了
There comes Tweedledum and Tweedledee.
你俩  人家在睡觉那
Guys, people are sleeping.
小点声    不好意思
MAN 1: Keep it down. KAT: Sorry.
开心点儿  帕伦蒂诺
MAN 2: Lighten up, Palladino.
摄象机是开着的吗?你们在拍吗?
Hey, is that on? Are you recording?
老妈  想你  老妈
Hi, Mom! Miss you, Mommy.
以此献给我在212号货船上的兄弟
This is for my buddies on Freighter 2-12!
献给你的!
Yeah, that's for you!
小凯!
Kat!
小凯  你以为你在干什么呢?
Kat, you want to tell me what the hell you think you're doing?
我只是在向我在舰队里的兄弟问好  长官
I was just saying hi to some of my buddies on the fleet, sir.
好嘛
Right.
就是说你在用屁屁讲话了?
So you were literally talking out of your ass.
算是吧
Kind of.
去吧  穿好衣服      是  长官
Go on, get dressed. Yes, sir.
康斯坦萨  出去
Castanza, get the hell out of here.
这是你最后一次到高级军官的房间里来  快走
It's the last time you come into senior officers' quarters. Go. Move.
你一定是我们在等的那位记者了
So, you must be the reporter we were expecting.
你不用为我刻意打扮
Well, you didn't have to dress for me.
戴安娜·贝丝  舰队新闻社的
D'Anna Biers, Fleet News Service.
李·阿达玛指挥官  空军指挥官  又叫CAG
Capt. Lee Adama, Commander of the Air Group, that's pronounced "CAG."
我建议你们尽快找一个出口
And I suggest you find yourselves an exit as soon as possible,
又叫ASAP (ASAP是"尽快"的缩写)
and that's pronounced, "ASAP."
我们该看的已经看完了
I think we've seen all we need to see here.
这是谁的好主意?
Whose brilliant idea was that?
你的家人是什么反应?
How did your family respond?
我入伍的时候我老爸像疯了一样
My Dad went crazy when I enlisted.
他认为军队就是笑料
He thought the military was a joke.
供给情感有缺陷的人和爱国的蠢货的避难所
A refuge for emotional cripples and patriotic fools.
但你还是参军了
But you signed up anyway.
我猜我只是想有所信仰
I guess I just wanted to believe in something.
这样就能增大存储容量?
You think it'll give it more memory?
恩  看来挺简单的  也许做些基本的调整就可以了
Yeah, it seems pretty simple. Maybe just a basic adjustment.
款式不错
It's a pretty good piece.
恩  用了好久了
Yeah, it's kind of old.
也许该换个了
D'ANNA: Maybe I need a new one.
到底怎么回事?
What the hell is going on?
不知道
I don't know.
不知道?我可是副总统
You don't know. I'm the Vice President.
她该来采访我  不是吗?
She's supposed to be interviewing me, isn't she?
可不  单从你的头衔来讲就代表尊重
Well, of course she should. Your title alone commands respect.
那是  这头衔在这里可是稀有商品
Of course it does. It's a rare commodity around here.
我是副总统啊
I mean, I'm the Vice President.
我不会主动去要求接受采访 这是肯定的了
I'm not gonna beg. I'll tell you that much.
贝丝女士 接下来…
DUALLA: Miss Biers, our next stop...
现在看来  盖尤斯 你可能要主动一些了
Now, Gaius, you may have to beg.
你要采取一切必要手段来保护我们的孩子
You'll do whatever's necessary to protect our child.
政治可能不是你的强项 可对我们来说却时有帮助
Politics may not be your strong suit, but it serves us in the moment.
相信我 这么做对我们有帮助
Trust me. This one can help us.
副总统先生
Mr. Vice President?
你好
Hello.
你好  戴安娜·贝丝 舰队新闻社的
Hi. D'Anna Biers, Fleet News Service.
你是记者
Oh, you're the reporter.
对了  阿达玛指挥官说过一个新闻部门可能会来
That's right. Cmdr. Adama said the News Service might be joining us.
我猜你...
I suppose you're,
正忙于采访  是这样吧?
well, very busy doing a lot of interviews, I would imagine.
我很乐意与你谈话
Well, I would love to speak to you.
如果你现在有时间就可以开始
If you've got a second, we can do it now.
不  恐怕不行 我很忙
No. I'm afraid not. I am very busy.
很忙  非常忙  日理万机
Really, really busy, at the moment. Snowed under.
但如果你和我的一个助理联系一下
But if you get in touch with one of my aides,
我明天可能会有一点时间
there might be a small window tomorrow.
显然我不能保证
I'm not promising anything, honestly.
但也许我能接受你的采访
But, I might be able to give you an interview then,
如果你们是这个意思的话
if that's what you would like.
好
Good.
好  好  那你们就继续吧
Good. Good. Well, you just carry on.
小怪人哦
What a strange little man.
阿达玛上尉 穿上衣服都认不出是你了
D'ANNA: Capt. Adama, I hardly recognized you with your clothes on.
我敢肯定你觉得那么做挺巧妙的
Look, I'm sure you thought it was clever
闯入了驾驶员的寝室  但是那区域禁止入内是有原因的
busting into the pilot's duty locker, but the area's off-limits for a reason.
那里是我的人可以放松  做回自己的地方
It's the one place where my people can unwind, be themselves.
看起来你认为你的驾驶员应得到特殊照顾
D'ANNA: You seem to think that your pilots deserve special consideration.
事实上  我确实是这么想的
Actually, I do.
像其他人一样
Like everyone else,
我的驾驶员失去了他们的家人 朋友
my pilots have lost their families, their friends,
他们曾经关心的人
everyone they ever cared about.
但在此之上
But on top of that,
他们每天都冒着生命的危险被派去...
they are asked to put their lives on the line every single day
保护一支更注重他们的过错
for a fleet that seems more interested in what they do wrong,
而不是他们的功劳的舰队
than in what they do right.
他们没有企求你们的怜悯 但他们绝对应得到你们的尊重
They're not asking for your pity, but they damn well deserve your respect.
老天  上士  都检查两次了
Gods, Chief, we've already run this up twice.
恩  可有些地方不对劲    什么?
Yeah, something doesn't feel right. What?
有些不对劲
Something doesn't feel right.
快点吧
Well, hurry up.
老天
That's it. Great.
好嘛  好极了
Oh, that's fantastic. That's just great.
我就知道  我怎么就没发现呢?
I knew it. How did I miss that?
也许你个笨蛋该多用些心思在维护上
Maybe if your knuckledraggers spent more time on maintenance
少花些时间到处去扯蛋
and less time frakking around.
笨蛋救了你的小命  长官
This knuckledragger just saved your ass, sir.
你再大点声啊  上士
Why don't you say that a little louder, Chief?
摄象机没有录上
I don't think the camera heard you.
什么 去他妈的摄象机 要惹我…
You know what? Frak the camera. You've been riding my...
别想试图反抗
Don't even try defending...
管他妈什么理由
...for no frakking reason!
离远点
Knock it off!
上士 修战机
Chief, fix the ship.
恩  去修战机
Yeah, fix the... Hey!
怎么的?    够了!
What? Hey, enough!
上士  修战机    你马上给我出去
Chief, fix your ship. You get the hell out of here, now.
别拍我
Get the camera out of my face.
她一周以来一直让我不爽
She has been pissing me off all week.
出了什么事?
What the hell's going on?
在给她换一换脑筋之前 我不会让她去值班
I'm taking her off rotation until she gets her head rewired. I mean...
不能那么做 我们需要驾驶员
Uh-uh. Can't do it. We need the pilots.
此外  如果谁对上士发脾气 我就要教训谁的话
Besides, if I scratched everyone who popped off at the Chief,
那只能让厨师来执行任务了
the cooks would be flying the missions.
他奶奶的
Son of a bitch.
全拍到了?  你高兴了?
Did you get all that? You happy?
走吧
Come on.
离开这里  走
Walk away.
我们从没受过维持人群秩序的训练
We were never trained for crowd control.
在遇袭的情况下 第一条命令就是保护自己和编队
First order of business when under attack is defend yourself and your squad.
但这些人都是平民
But these were civilians.
我缝了10针 就可以证明我们受到攻击了
I have 10 stitches that say we were under attack.
事实是  泰派我们去补给船就是糟糕的命令
Truth is, it was a command frak-up the moment Tigh put us on that supply ship.
有人要干掉那个醉熏熏的混蛋 我也不觉得奇怪
I'm not surprised someone's trying to take out that drunk son of a bitch.
好了  大兵  别说了
All right. Private. Belay that.
泰上校受人威胁了?
Col. Tigh's been threatened?
不  采访结束 把那东西关了
No. This interview's over. Shut that off.
指挥官
Commander.
请小心脚下
Watch your step, please.
好  来吧
Okay, come on.
军情报告?
Sitrep.
舰队安静祥和 过去的10天里没有发现敌人
Fleet's quiet, no enemy contact for the last 10 days.
总之  没发现赛昂人
No Cylon contact, anyway.
他们有他们的工作 我们也一样
Well, they have their job to do. We have ours.
听说了要在星云九号上开会了吗?
Did you hear about the meeting on Cloud Nine?
舰队里的代表从四面八方乘船飞来
Reps flying in from every vessel in the fleet
就为参加个大型的狗屁会议 ?   恩  我听说了
for a king-size bitch session? Yeah, I've heard.
他们发给我们一封邀请函 让我们派个代表
Well, they sent us an invitation to send a delegation.
你去吧
You're it.
拿开一下好吗?
Do you mind?
不  不  你们继续
D'ANNA: No, no. Go ahead.
加把劲儿
We're in.
我现在可不是舰队里最受欢迎的人
I'm not exactly the most popular guy in the fleet right now.
让那些批评家知道你不怕他们会好一些
Well, it'll be good then, to let your cutters know that you're not afraid of them
你是这么认为的? 以为我在逃避?
That what you think? I've been hiding?
到底是怎么回事  比尔?
What the hell is going on here, Bill?
你这么做的时间太长了 动机令人担忧
You've been doing this too long. We were worried about ulterior motives.
你去那里是因为你不害怕 该让大家看到这点
You're going because you're not afraid and people should see that.
此外  还要给人们一个机会去发泄他们的感情
Plus, it'll also give people a chance to vent their feelings
而不是闷在心里
instead of seething in private.
最后一点就是 我想你也需要放松一下
And finally, I think you need a little R&R.
所以仔细考虑一下这次短暂的必要旅行
ADAMA: So consider this mandatory shore leave.
放松一下  休息一下
Take a swim. Get some sleep.
长官
Sir.
还有...
And
离酒吧远点儿
stay away from the bar.
3个 有3个人  人不少啊
Three. There's three. So, you got lots.
祝你好运  上校 在星云九号上玩的开心
STARBUCK: Good luck, Colonel. Have fun on Cloud Nine.
会的
TIGH: You bet.
开始飞行前准备
PILOT: Initiating pre-flight.
怎么回事?
What's going on?
取消飞行!大家快出去!
Abort launch! Everybody out, now!
退后!大家快退后!
Everybody back. Get back, now.
怎么回事?
What's going on?
主保险丝爆了 看起来好象有人偷工减料了
The main bus is totaled. Looks like somebody took a hammer to it.
如果在运输过程中出了这事 那舱内的一切将直接被喷到太空里
If this had blown in transit, the cabin would have vented to space.
有人想谋害你  索尔
Someone's trying to kill you, Saul.
明目张胆
Comes with the stripes.
就因为那次该死的吉迪恩事件
It's because of that damned Gideon incident.
艾伦  不一定因为这事
Ellen, we don't know that.
就是这事
Of course we do.
戴安娜·贝丝已经留了两条信息
D'Anna Biers left two messages already.
这是给你解释自己的机会
She's giving you the chance to tell your side.
我用不着为自己去做解释 尤其是向她
I don't have to explain myself, especially to her.
罗丝琳想要安抚舰队
Roslin wants to placate the fleet,
把伟大的比尔·阿达玛重新推上王座
put the great Bill Adama back on his pedestal.
做到这一点的捷径就是拿你示众
The fastest way to do that is by hanging you out to dry.
你说为什么阿达玛派你去星云九号?
Why do you think Adama wanted to send you to Cloud Nine?
吉迪恩事件是我当班的时候造成的
The Gideon happened on my watch.
对
Yes.
但你没命令那些陆战队员开火啊
But you didn't order those jar-heads to open fire.
你就是这样啊  索尔
This is so like you, Saul.
一直都是一名自豪的士兵 承担责难  因为这样才光荣
Always the proud soldier, taking the heat because it's honorable.
你什么时候才能认识到我们在这里都是人人为己?
When are you going to realize we're all alone out here?
去打仗的时候你害怕吗?
D'ANNA: Are you afraid when you go into combat?
他们告诉你的第一件事就是 要假设自己已经死掉了
First thing they tell you is to assume you're already dead.
听起来好残忍
D'ANNA: Well, that sounds ghoulish.
恩  也许吧
Yeah, maybe.
可死人在遇袭的时候 不会害怕或被吓呆了
But dead men don't get scared or freeze up under fire.
我只担心地狱会是一个孤独的地方
Me, I'm just worried that hell's going to be a lonely place
我要尽我所能把那里塞满赛鬼子
and I'm gonna fill it up with every toaster son of a bitch I find.
对你来说最困难的事情是什么?
D'ANNA: What's been the hardest for you?
他们想让你撇开人性的那一面因为那样会害死你
They try to turn off the human part of you because that's what'll get you killed
可是当你到了战场上的时候 想做到这点并不那么容易
But when you're out in the field, it's not that easy.
在战场上做什么事都没那么容易
Nothing's that easy.
给你5分钟
GUARD: You got five minutes.
莎伦? 是我
Sharon? It's me.
莎伦!
Sharon!
把你的手电给我
Give me your light.
你在说什么?
GUARD: What the hell are you talking about?
快把手电给我! 有些不对劲!
Give me your light, now. Something's wrong.
老天  去叫卡托医生
Oh, gods. Call Dr. Cottle.
快!
HELO: Now!
那东西有助于你缓解压力吗?
D'ANNA: Does that help you cope with the stress?
没多大作用
Not really.
我只是想成为一艘太空堡垒上的军官
Look, all that I ever wanted was to be an officer on a Battlestar.
一直以来 我比队里的每个人都更刻苦训练
Okay, I trained my whole life, trained harder than anyone in my unit.
在我被分派到卡拉狄加之前 我从没享受过生活
Basically, I put my life on hold until I was assigned to Galactica.
然后赛昂人发动进攻 我才认识到我只懂得这些事
Then the Cylons hit and I realized that this is all that I know.
技术操作  指挥  战术
Tech manuals, commands, and tactics.
我不是说做这份工作我不开心
You know, I'm not saying that I'm unhappy.
只是想尝试一些新事物
Just wondering if there's something more.
你有什么发现呢?
D'ANNA: And what have you discovered?
我讨厌香烟
I hate cigarettes.
安宝莎确实不错
Ambrosia's good with a chaser.
如果你喝得够多的话...
And if you have enough ambrosia,
就不会感到那么痛了
they don't really hurt that much.
好了  我们尽量让你少受点罪
There you go. We'll make this as painless as possible.
喝酒吗?
Drink?
这是采访  还是鸡尾酒会?
Is this an interview or a cocktail party?
开玩笑吗? 我们是以此来放松的
Are you kidding? This is how we keep it painless.
只是想让采访自然些
Just like to keep it casual, that's all.
请
Please.
干杯  上校
Cheers, Colonel.
干杯
Cheers.
在我们开始之前...
D'ANNA: Before we begin,
我听到很多谣传 有人向你发出了…
I had heard rumors that, that you had death threats
死亡威胁的警告  是吗?
leveled against you. Is that right?
这是一艘军舰  谣言随处可见
This is a military vessel. We have rumors for every occasion.
当你的朋友受伤后 接替他的领导地位对你来说很难吗?
Was it hard for you to take over your friend's command when he was shot?
我没有接替什么 指挥权落到了我的身上 我就要担起重任
I didn't take anything. Command fell to me and I did my duty.
但你作为卡拉狄加的全权指挥一周多的时间
D'ANNA: But you were in full command of Galactica for more than a week,
然后在那段时间里 采取了一些具有争议性的行动
and in that time there were a number of controversial actions taken.
你是说吉迪恩吧
You're talking about the Gideon.
我做出的是军事决定
I made a military decision.
再有类似情况  我还会那么做
Given the same circumstances, I'd do it again.
这么说你没有丝毫悔意?
So you have no regrets, whatsoever?
你想陷害我
You're trying to set me up!
上校  你说为什么没有针对 "吉迪恩惨案"的…
Colonel, why do you think there was no official investigation
官方调查呢?
into the Gideon Massacre?
请…
Please come.
一边去!
Get out of my face!
拍到了吗?
Did you get that?
是的
Got it.
有些人耍酒疯
Someone's a mean drunk.
好极了 我需要一名陪练
Great. I could use a sparring partner.
抱歉 我没带手套来
Sorry. I didn't bring my gloves.
可惜啊
Too bad.
阿达玛上尉说我可以问你有关新驾驶员的事
Capt. Adama said that I could ask you about the new pilots.
恩  阿达玛上尉喜欢给我找麻烦事
Yeah, well, Capt. Adama likes to push my buttons.
你在新兵中想要寻找些什么?
So, what do you look for in a new recruit?
配合
Coordination.
良好的反射神经
Good reflexes.
十分敬业
Total commitment.
还有最主要的是在战斗中可以疯狂追随我的人
Most of all, someone crazy enough to follow me into combat.
上校  你说为什么没有针对 "吉迪恩惨案"的…
D'ANNA: Colonel, why do you think there was no official investigation
官方调查呢?
into the Gideon massacre?
请…
D'ANNA: Please come.
一边去!
TIGH: Get out of my face.
我要对泰上校的行为道歉 那样做是不应该的
I want to apologize for Col. Tigh's behavior. It was uncalled for.
好象几年来
Seems like a lot of people have been
许多人都在替他道歉  指挥官
apologizing for him over the years, Commander.
和我坦率地说吧
So level with me.
为什么泰上校没有因吉迪恩事件而受到指控?
Why is Col. Tigh not being charged in the Gideon incident?
我们在与一个...
We're at war against an enemy
强大无比的敌人战斗
with a vastly superior force.
我不会把仅有的几个在公众暴行祭坛上活下来的人作为祭品
I will not sacrifice the few people we have left on the altar of public outrage.
4名平民死亡
So four civilians are dead
泰和开枪的人却都逍遥法外了
and Tigh and the shooters take a walk.
没人会逍遥法外
Nobody takes a walk.
我们将一直背负这一切
We all gotta live with it.
蝮蛇战机5-9-1号  我是卡拉狄加 你可以降落了
KELLY: Viper five-niner-one Galactica, you are cleared into the break.
左舷降落台  手动近接 检验器为绿色  可以看到降落台
Portside landing bay hands-on approach. Checkers are green. Call the ball.
可以看到降落台
KAT: Roger ball.
等下  见鬼
Wait a second, guys. Damn it!
速度2-0-5
Speed two-zero-five.
加大推进力  小凯 你落到滑翔道以下了
Keep your power up, Kat, you're dropping below glideslope.
操控杆不好用了
Controls are messed up.
拜托...
Come on.
还是太低了  离舰重飞  小凯  离舰重飞
Still too low. Wave off, Kat. Wave off!
到底怎么回事? 这是她第3次重飞了
What the hell is going on? That is her third wave-off.
当我们发现了一个目标
When we make a contact,
编队万分火急地集合到一起
the squadron's got seconds to put it all together.
飞行前最终检查  武器检查  通讯
Pre-flight, weapons check, communications,
如果有一个差错  我们就完蛋了
one mistake, we're a smear in the cockpit.
我不明白  她是想…
I don't understand, is she trying to...
妈的闭嘴  小凯
Shut the frak up. Kat.
按我说的去做  好吗?
STARBUCK: We're gonna do this, okay?
节流阀摆到中间位置  然后调到近接位置
Leave the throttle alone down the middle, then chop it at the come-on in close
然后降落到甲板上    操作杆不对劲
and feel for the deck. KAT: The controls are messed up.
我能感觉得到
I can't feel it.
我做不来
I can't do it.
小凯  我们训练的时候练习过
Kat, we did this all through training,
像从前一样  你能行的
okay? You're gonna stick this, just like before.
不
KAT: No.
蝮蛇战机5-9-1  我是卡拉狄加
Viper five-niner-one Galactica,
你可以降落了  看到降落台了
you are cleared into the break. Call the ball.
太低了  5-9-1  离舰重飞  重飞
Too low, five-niner-one. Wave off!
不  她能降落的! 小凯  快按住节流阀!
No, she's putting down! Kat, full throttle now.
我能感觉得到...
I can't feel it.
当你作战成功归来后
When you came back after a successful run,
比享用一顿丰盛的大餐还要好
let me tell you, it is better than a great meal.
比中大奖  做爱还要爽
Better than hitting a jackpot. It's better than sex.
我做不来...
KAT: I can't do it.
她错过了格栅
She missed the trap.
检修组  急救员到左舷降落台报道
Damage control, medics, report to portside hangar bay.
急救员到左舷降落台报道
WOMAN ON P.A.: Medics to portside hangar bay.
到底出了什么事? 小凯上百次没错过格栅
What the hell happened? Kat's made the trap 100 times.
恩  我看第101次最难搞啊
Yeah, I guess 101 was a real bitch, huh?
放开我!放开我!
KAT: Let go of me. Let me go.
嗨
STARBUCK: Hey.
小凯!
Kat!
我是星芭儿  你没事了  到家了
It's Starbuck. You're okay. You're home!
家?家里早毁了! 我们得离开这!他们会杀了我们!
Home? Home is dead. We gotta get out of here, they're gonna kill us!
这是什么?兴奋剂?
STARBUCK: What are these, stims?
求你!别拿走!
Please don't do this.
放开我!
KAT: Let go.
不!放开我!
No! Let go!
放开我!
KAT: Let go of me!
我们会死的!
We're gonna die!
快把我的驾驶员送到医务室去
STARBUCK: Get my pilot to sick bay now.
兴奋剂  看她的样子 已经吃了一把了
Stims. By the look of it, she's been taking them by the handful.
嗨
Hey.
你敢碰我试试!
SHARON: Don't you dare touch me.
听我说
COTTLE: Listen to me.
你要干什么!?
What are you doing?
听我说 我在救你的孩子!
COTTLE: Listen to me. I'm trying to save your baby.
按住她!    这里是禁区!
Hold her still! GUARD: This is a restricted area.
指挥官  她在这里
GIARD: Commander, she's over here.
阿达玛指挥官 那女人看起来和以前的沃莱瑞中尉一模一样
Cmdr. Adama, that woman looks just like the late Lt. Valerii.
请交出录象带
The tape, please.
为什么要在卡拉狄加上藏匿赛昂人?
Why would Galactica be harboring a Cylon?
录象带
The tape.
那孩子活下来了吗?
Did the baby survive?
你是否知道这事即使泄露了一点
You understand that even a hint of this could be devastating
都会对舰队的士气造成毁灭性的打击
to the morale in the fleet.
你总是喜欢把事情说得很悬
You are the master of understatement.
你知不知道  在吉迪恩事件后 这事会让整个舰队都反对你
You know, after the Gideon, this could turn the entire fleet against you.
那真正的问题就在于 这么做对你来说是否重要
Then the real question is, whether or not it matters to you.
我对像你这样怀疑我的爱国精神的人痛恨的要命
You know, I am sick to death of people like you questioning my patriotism.
我们都想让这支舰队存活下去
We all want this fleet to survive.
我觉得你做的很好 在这种情况下  非常好
I think you're doing very well. Very well, under the circumstances.
我知道这对于你来说是一份苦差事
I understand this has been a difficult job for you.
我听说你的报道
I mean, I hear that your reports haven't exactly
并没有讨好指挥官  是吧?
ingratiated you with the Commander, have they?
或是说全体船员
Or the rest of the crew, for that matter.
仍然幸运的是  作为平民政府中的一员
Still, luckily, as a member of the civilian government,
我可以向你保证我不会有任何保留
I'm here to assure you that I have no such reservations.
可我相信大部分的船员会理解我只是在工作
I think most of the crew understands I'm just doing my job.
大家都一样  我们都是在工作  不是吗?
As are we all. All just doing our jobs, aren't we?
我在做我的工作  你在做你的工作
I'm just doing my job. You're just doing your job.
好了  该说正经事了  盖尤斯
Okay. Cut to the chase, Gaius.
告诉她为什么该由你来领导这支舰队
Tell her why you deserve to lead this fleet.
当我被困在科波上的时候
As I myself discovered, when I was stranded,
我发现...
stranded on Kobol,
我发现了自己在此之前并不知道的
I found that the stress of survival revealed
在求生压力下所具有的领导能力
leadership qualities that previously I didn't even know that I possessed.
真的    是吗?
Really. Yeah?
我听说你的团队有死有伤
I understand your party took several casualties.
是的  那很不幸
Yes. That was very unfortunate.
他们每个人都是英雄
They were heroes, every one.
我准备好了  我们可以开始了吗?
You know what, I'm ready. Shall we shoot this one?
大概是假警报  不用理会  好
Oh, it's probably just a false alarm. Ignore it. You're okay.
比尔你去机库 我去作战信息中心    快去!
Bill, you take the hangar deck. I'm gonna take the CIC. Go.
拜托  这下面安全的很  真的
Please. You're as safe as houses down here. Really.
赛昂突袭机来袭  这不是演习 重复  各就各位  各就各位
MAN ON P.A.: Incoming Cylon Raiders. This is not a drill. Repeat.
那是娱乐新闻
That's showbiz.
什么情况?
What have we got?
两架突袭机  急速来袭
Two Raiders, closing fast.
长官  赛昂突袭机与卡拉狄加呈C.B.D.R.状态
Sir, the Cylon Raiders are on CBDR with Galactica.
速度为2-2.79
Speed two-two-point-seven-niner.
杜亚拉  C.B.D.R.是什么?
Dualla, what's CBDR?
"方位不变  范围递减--即截击航向"
Constant bearing, decreasing range. A collision course.
巡逻机在哪里?
TIGH: Where the hell's the CAP?
舰队的另一边  长官
DUALLA: Other side of the fleet, sir.
待战机紧急升空 整个舰队一级戒备
Scramble the alert fighters. Set Condition 1 throughout the entire fleet.
为以防万一 让他们开启超光速驱动器
Have them spool up their FTLs, just in case.
快!快!快!动起来!
Let's go. Let's go. Let's go. Move. Move.
清理这块甲板  把这东西拿走
HOTDOG: Clear this deck. Get this out of here.
什么战况?
What's the sitrep?
两架敌机  来势凶猛
Two bandits, coming hard.
打起精神  跟着我们就是了
Just keep your eyes open and follow us.
好了  快  让战机进入发射管道 把它们送出去
All right, let's go. Let's get the birds in the hole. Let's go move them out.
把这梯子拿走
Get this flyer out of here.
快  快  后撤 把这管子拿开
Let's go. Move them fools out of here.
第一小队已经进入发射管道
First team in the tubes.
小杜  驾驶员在线
Dee. Pilots on speaker.
你与你父亲和解了吗?
D'ANNA: Did you ever come to terms with your dad?
我没给他机会  我们的最后一次谈话…
I wouldn't let him. The last time we talked, it got
破裂了
heated.
我告诉他以后再也不想见到他
I told him I never wanted to see him again.
三周后  赛昂人来袭
Three weeks later, the Cylons attacked.
好  我是新手    应该感到害怕吗?
Okay, so I'm new at this. Should I be scared?
反正我害怕
I am.
好了  各位  最后一架战机已经起飞了 打扫一下机库
All right, people, that's it. Last bird's away, let's clear the nest.
准备修复工作
Get this deck ready for recovery.
快!快!快!动起来!
Let's go! Let's go! Let's go! Move. Move.
长官  待战机出动了
Sir, Alert Vipers are away.
弹药管制报告 武器就位  准备完毕
Gun Control reports weapons manned and ready.
我是阿波罗  检查无线电
APOLLO: Apollo, wireless check.
我是星芭儿  听到了
STARBUCK: Starbuck, I'm hearing you.
我是热狗  1-4-1  清清楚楚
HOTDOG: Hotdog one-four-one, loud and clear.
我是格雷斯特  清清楚楚
GRAYSHIRT: Grayshirt, loud and clear.
我是金斯顿 很清楚
KINGSTON: Kingston, you're good.
我是阿波罗 两架赛昂突袭机  呈密集队形
Apollo. Tally two Cylon Raiders, close formation.
我是星芭儿  收到
This is Starbuck. Roger that. Roger formation.
准备交火  武器准备完毕
APOLLO: Prepare engage. Weapons hot.
发现目标  重复  发现目标
Targets in view. Repeat. Targets in view.
锁定6-1-2-1  武器瞄准2-4-1
Locked six-four-two-one.
收到
Copy that.
正与赛昂突袭机交火 正与赛昂突袭机交火
Engaging Cylon Raiders. Engaging Cylon Raiders.
他们呈分散队型 热狗  紧跟着我
STARBUCK: They're breaking formation. Hotdog, stick with me.
收到
HOTDOG: Roger that.
来吧  你他妈个…
Come on, you...
我失控了 我看不到图像了
HOTDOG: I've got no joy, I lost visual!
我的操纵杆被损坏
They're throwing me right on my stick.
加油  星芭儿
Come on, Starbuck.
热狗  突袭机在你左侧8点方向  交给我吧  锁定他了
STARBUCK: Hotdog, Raider's on your left eight. I'm on him. I got him.
好!干掉一个!
Yeah! Splash one!
瞄准第2架突袭机
Targeting second Raider.
我是金斯顿  敌机要撤退  想逃跑
KINGSTON: Kingston, Bandit's taking off. Take evasive action.
我来搞定他  金斯顿  来吧
APOLLO: I've got him, Kingston, come on. Come to papa.
该死!开火啊!
Damn it, take the shot.
击落了!
APOLLO: That's a kill. Yes.
好!
Outstanding.
雷达没有发现目标  指挥官
Dradis shows clear, Commander.
我是指挥官
This is the Commander.
成功拦截  击落赛昂突袭机 干得好  各位
TIGH: Cylon Raiders have been intercepted and destroyed. Good work, people.
收到  卡拉狄加  我们返回母舰吧
STARBUCK: Roger that, Galactica. Let's head back to the bird farm.
取消紧急状态 变成三级戒备
Secure from Action Stations. Set Condition 3.
盖塔先生 你来接管这里
Mr. Gaeta, you have the deck.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
全船三级戒备
Set Condition 3 throughout the ship.
重复  全船三级戒备
Repeat. Set Condition 3.
这工作越来越轻松了吗?
Does this ever get any easier?
不  女士
No, ma'am.
更难了
It gets harder.
谢谢
Thank you.
十五度？
Was 15 degrees?
十六
Sixteen.
战斗进行的怎么样?
So, how'd it go out there?
我们没有伤亡  这就不错了
Well, we didn't lose anyone. That's a good day.
艾伦
Ellen?
我看我还不能从中组成一个故事
I'm not sure I've found a story in all this yet.
倒回去一点
Go back a bit.
对 这里
Yeah. There.
我知道这本书
I know that book.
那是柯泰洛斯写的书
That's by Kataris.
怎么了  上校? 要喝酒吗?
What's wrong, Colonel? Need a drink?
去下地狱吧
You can go to hell.
我去过了 那里叫做吉迪恩
I've been there. It was called Gideon.
我寝食难安
I can't eat. I can't sleep.
看到他们的一张张脸
I see their faces.
他们不是赛昂人 他们是活生生的人
Those weren't Cylons we attacked, those were real people.
他们和我爸一样
They looked like my dad.
和我小弟一样
They looked like my little brother.
这么做也与事无补
This isn't gonna change anything.
至少吉迪恩上的人会瞑目了
At least the people on the Gideon will have their justice.
如果是为了这样  那开枪吧
If that's what this is about, then do it.
会的  我会开枪的
I will. I'll do it.
总要有人为发生在那艘船上的事付出代价
Somebody has to pay for what happened on that ship.
当时是我指挥 是我派你去那里的 错在我
I was in command, I sent you there, it's my fault.
来吧  孩子
Come on, son.
开枪吧
Do it.
吉迪恩那次是一场意外 这次却是你擅作主张
Gideon was an accident. This is a choice.
上校    这里没事了
Colonel. TIGH: We're all right here.
走吧  中尉
Let's go, Lieutenant.
你到一边去好吗?
Would you get out of my face?
为什么要这么做?  小凯
What made you do it, Kat?
我当时很累
I was tired.
一直没睡觉
Haven't gotten any sleep.
觉得自己快要崩溃了 我不知道如何是好
I felt like I was losing my edge. I don't know what else to do.
难道不能和别人说吗?
Couldn't you talk to someone?
去和谁说?大家都一样
Who am I gonna talk to? We're all in the same hole.
没有替补
Okay, there are no replacements coming up.
没有假日 只能这样
There's no down time. This is it.
所以我就开始服用兴奋剂
So I started taking stims.
你犯了错误  这事常有
D'ANNA: You made a mistake. It happens.
恩  除了没人去驾驶我的战机了
KAT: Yeah, except now my flight's a pilot short.
那些人  他们和我一样疲乏
Those guys, they're just as tired
一样惨兮兮的  可他们依旧在坚持
and they're just as messed up as I was, but they're still laying it on the line.
我拼尽全力来守卫这支舰队
I've worked my ass off defending this fleet.
我沮丧过  生气过
I've been frustrated. I've been angry.
还经历了一些你不可能想象到的事
I've been everything that you can possibly think of.
这是我第一次...感到...羞愧
But this is the first time that I've felt ashamed.
我看够了
I've seen enough.
停
Kill it.
我理解你看到这些可能觉得不好受
Look. I understand this might be hard for you to watch...
这是恶意诽谤  舰队早把我们当作是…
It's a hatchet job. The fleet already thinks we're
一群好战分子 这恰好证实了这一点
a bunch of trigger-happy assassins, this just confirms it.
你把我们的丑事全抖搂了出来
You show us with our pants down and our asses hanging out.
你就没什么说的吗?
Don't you have anything to say?
我觉得很好
I think it's great.
我认为她完全按我们的要求完成了工作
ADAMA: I think she did exactly what we asked her to do.
让大家看到舰队的守护神也是人  实话实说
She put a human face on the guardians of the fleet. Warts and all.
我为此感到骄傲
I'm proud of it.
你可以展示给整个舰队看了
You can show it to the entire fleet.
再好不过了
Doesn't get better than that.
我想看一下结尾
I'd like to see the end.
我也是
So would I.
恩  继续吧
Go ahead. Yeah.
我来卡拉狄加是为了向大家讲述一个故事
D'ANNA: I came to Galactica to tell a story.
坦白地说  在我到那之前
In all honesty, I thought
我以为自己早已经知道了这个故事
I knew what that story was, before I ever set foot there.
一支傲慢的军队是如何因为利己主义
How an arrogant military let their egos get in the way of doing their jobs.
而防碍了他们保卫民众生命的工作
Safeguarding the lives of the civilian population.
但我发现事实却更为复杂
But I found out that the truth was more complex than that.
这些人不是赛昂人
These people aren't Cylons.
他们不是那些盲目地服从命令 然后替人效劳的机器人
They're not robots blindly following orders and polishing their boots.
他们是人
They're people.
缺点很多  是的 但同时也充满人性
Deeply flawed, yes. But deeply human, too.
也许这正说明了他们是人
And maybe that's saying the same thing.
最为打动我的是  尽管经受了艰难困苦
What struck me most is that, despite it all,
各种压力  时刻都有丧命的危险
the hardships, the stress, the ever-present danger of being killed.
这一切从未使他们放弃过
Despite all that, they never give up.
他们从没轻言放弃  坐以待毙
They never lie down on the road and let the truck run them over.
而是早上醒来  穿上军装  投入工作
They wake up in the morning, put on their uniforms and do their jobs.
每一天  没有回报  没有休息
Every day. No pay. No rest.
没想过丢掉自身的重任  而让他人取而代之
No hope of ever laying down the burden and letting someone else do the job.
没有援军会来
There are no relief troops coming.
没有殖民舰队每天训练新入伍的军人
No Colonial fleet training new recruits every day.
有的只是卡拉狄加上的人
The people on Galactica are it.
他们就是分开我们和赛昂人的那道细细的警戒线
They are the thin line of blue that separates us from the Cylons.
盖塔中尉曾告诉过我一项了不起的数据
Lt. Gaeta told me a remarkable statistic.
在卡拉狄加上没有一名船员提出过辞职 一名都没有
Not a single member of Galactica's crew has asked to resign. Not one.
想一想吧
Think about that.
如果你穿上了军装  难道就不想辞职吗?
If you wore the uniform, wouldn't you want to quit?
站到一旁说:"够了  让别人来保护舰队吧"
To step aside and say, "Enough. Let someone else protect the fleet. "
我知道我会这么说的
I know I would.
可我并没有身着军装
But then, I don't wear a uniform.
我们中的绝大多数人都没穿 绝大多数人也永远不会去穿
Most of us don't, and most of us never will.
卡拉狄加的故事并不是关于人们在压力之下 做出了错误的决定
The story of Galactica isn't that people make bad decisions under pressure.
而是那些错误是例外
It's that those mistakes are the exception.
在绝大多数情况下 阿达玛指挥官的部下都会顺利地完成工作
Most of the time, the men and women serving under Cmdr. Adama get it right.
证据就是我们的舰队存活了下来
The proof is that our fleet survives.
在卡拉狄加的保护之下 我们会坚持下去
And with Galactica at our side, we will endure.
我是舰队新闻社的戴安娜·贝丝
This is D' Anna Biers. Fleet News Service.
在整个舰队播出了
That was shown across their entire fleet.
他们的恢复力很了不起
Their resilience is remarkable.
播放被剪掉的片段
Play the footage that was cut.
你要干什么? 住手!
SHARON: What are you doing? Stop it.
我在救你的孩子
COTTLE: I'm trying to save your baby.
这里是禁区
GUARD: This is a restricted area!
放开我
SHARON: Get off of me.
我还活着 她还活着
I'm still alive. She's still alive!
我早和你说过
I told you.
难以置信
That's incredible.
那孩子呢?
And the baby?
得救了
D'ANNA: It was saved.
我们为了向舰队转播图象 而损失了两架突袭机
We lost two Raiders relaying the images back to the fleet,
可我想这点牺牲是值得的
but I think the sacrifice was worth it.
我们必须小心行事
We must proceed with caution.
不惜一切代价保护那孩子的生命
The child's life must be protected at all costs.
是啊
Yeah.
真是一个神迹啊
It truly is a miracle from God.